(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
2022/1/30 21:00 3DLIVE
ポルカプロデュース! 最強アイドルグループ3DLIVE!
Polka Produces! The Strongest Idol Group 3DLIVE!
#尾丸ポルカ生誕祭
#OmaruPolkaBirthdayFestival
5!
4!
3!
2!
1!
0!
はじまるよー!
It's starting!
楽しみ!
Can't wait!
このホロパ組をプロデュース
Producing this Holopa group
お待たせしました!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
いくぞー!
Let's go!
わっしょい!
Wasshoi!
ポルカちゃーん!
Polka-chan!
準備はいい?
Are you ready?
ワン・ツー!
One, two!
ポルPプロデュース!
Produced by Pol-P!
最強のアイドル!
The strongest idols!
ホロライブ3期生!
Hololive Gen 3!
いくよ!
Here we go!
応援してね!
Please cheer for us!
よっしゃー!
Alright!
始まるぞ!
It's starting!
せーーの!
One, two!
最高!
Awesome!
盛り上がっていこう!
Let's get hyped!
いくぞいくぞ!
Let's go, let's go!
3DLIVE!
スタート!
Start!
さぁ 始まるよ
Now, it's starting
(Ready Go!)
せーの! で駆け出そう
Ready, set, go! Let's start running
(Ready Go!)
眩しい光の先へ
Towards the dazzling light
(Ready Go!)
君に届くように
So it reaches you
(Ready Go!)
どこまでも続く
Continuing on forever
(Ready Go!)
世界を照らそう
Let's light up the world
(Ready Go!)
Shiny Smily Story
終わらない夢を
A dream that never ends
これからも
From now on too
(Ready Go!)
ずっと ずっと
Always and forever
(Ready Go!)
笑っていようよ
Let's keep on smiling
(Ready Go!)
一緒に歩こう
Let's walk together
(Ready Go!)
Shiny Smily Story
きらめきを放て
Release your sparkle
君の元へ
Right to you
本日は「目指せ！最強アイドル決勝戦」にご来場いただき、誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for coming to today's "Aim for it! Strongest Idol Final Battle."
ライブビューイングの方に向けても、開演に先立ちましてお願い申し上げます。
To those in live viewing as well, we have some requests before the show begins.
ライブビューイングの方は、どなたでも声を上げる行為、ペンライトなどを振る行為は制限されておりません。
For those in live viewing, shouting and waving penlights are not restricted for anyone.
Twitterのハッシュタグは #尾丸ポルカ誕生日2022 でつぶやきください。
Please tweet using the Twitter hashtag #OmaruPolkaBirthday2022.
Twitterのハッシュタグは #尾丸ポルカ生誕祭 でつぶやきください。
Please tweet using the Twitter hashtag #OmaruPolkaBirthFestival.
スクリーンショットの撮影も自由となっております。
Taking screenshots is also allowed.
ホロアリーナにおいでの客さまは、お席について今しばらくお待ちください。
Guests at the Holo Arena, please take your seats and wait a little longer.
本日はご来場いただき誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for joining us today.
開演に先立ちまして、ご来場のお客様にお願い申し上げます。
Before the show begins, we have a few requests for the guests in attendance.
客席内での飲食はご遠慮ください。また、全館禁煙となっております。
Please refrain from eating and drinking in the seating area. Also, the entire building is non-smoking.
携帯電話、アラーム付き腕時計などは…必ず電源をお切りくださいますよう、ご協力お願いいたします。
Please ensure your mobile phones, alarm watches, etc. are turned off... we appreciate your cooperation.
また、許可のない写真撮影、録音、録画は固くお断りいたします。
Also, unauthorized photography, audio recording, and video recording are strictly prohibited.
まもなく開演でございます。
The show will start shortly.
アイドルの頂点が今日、ここに決まる。
The top of idols will be decided here today.
決勝まで勝ち上がってきた尾丸ポルカプロデュースの「ホロバックプロジェクト」。この6人が一体どんなパフォーマンスを見せてくれるのでしょうか。
The "Holoback Project" produced by Omaru Polka, who fought their way to the finals. What kind of performance will these six show us?
死んでも夢を叶えたい
I want to fulfill my dreams even if I die
いいえ、死んでも夢は叶えられる
No, dreams can be fulfilled even if I die
それは絶望？それとも希望？
Is it despair? Or is it hope?
過酷な運命乗り越えて
Overcoming a cruel fate
脈がなくても突き進む
Moving forward even without a pulse
それが私達のサガだから
Because that is our destiny
徒花ネクロマンシー
Adabana Necromancy
誰が弔う
Who will mourn?
死地は彼方
The place of death is far away
静寂を破り
Breaking the silence
芽吹いた夢を
The dream that budded
誓え
Swear
穿て
Pierce
重なる屍
Piling up corpses
高みへ届くまで
Until reaching the heights
唸れ
Roar
徒花
Useless flowers
朽ち果てても進め
Even if decayed, move forward
奪わせはしない尊厳の愚弄に
I won't let it be taken away, the mockery of dignity
飢餓を解き放て
Release the hunger
枯れても走ることを命と呼べ
Call the act of running even when withered, life
空に叫ぶ脱・生存の定義
Crying out to the sky, the definition of escape-survival
骨を斬らせて
Letting bones be cut
闇を断って
Cutting through the darkness
雲間に光る
Shining through the clouds
簒奪の勝機
A chance for victory through usurpation
覚悟を宿命に突きつけて
Thrusting resolve into destiny
天下に狂い咲くサガサガ
Madly blooming throughout the land, Saga, Saga
傷ひとつない手など愚か
Hands without a single scratch are foolish
意思も自由もその身も投げて
Throwing away will, freedom, and even that body
守れ
Protect
退くな
Do not retreat
涙も血も無い
Without tears or blood
神話を築くまで
Until building a myth
燃えろ修羅花
Burn, Ashura-flower
鼓動なき世界で
In a world without a heartbeat
摂理に抗い天命も無礼に
Opposing providence, making even heaven's will rude
腐鎖切り抜けて
Cutting through the chains
心を無くすことが死と知れ
Know that losing one's heart is death
極めて儚い偶像の寵児
The extremely fleeting favorite child of idols
目には目を剥き牙を剥き
Turning eye for eye, baring fangs
牙を剥け
Bare your fangs
いつか誰もが散華する捨て石
Someday everyone will fall like scattered petals, like sacrificial stones
輝け　刹那無限の火花
Shine, the infinite sparks of a moment
乱世に迸る
Gushing out into the turbulent world
SAGA! SAGA!
何が神の冒涜か
What is blasphemy against God?
裁きなどさせない
I won't let you judge me
希望　高らかに打ち鳴らせ
Let hope ring out loudly
呼吸よりも生きた証
A proof of life more than breath itself
徒花
Idle flower
まだまだ朽ち果てても進め
Go forward even if you rot away
奪わせはしない
I won't let you take it
尊厳の愚弄に
To the mockery of dignity
飢餓を解き放て
Unleash the hunger
枯れても走る
Run even if withered
ことを命と呼べ
Call it 'life'
空に叫ぶ　生存の定義
Shout the definition of survival to the sky
骨を斬らせて
Let them cut my bones
闇を断って
Sever the darkness
雲間に光る
Shining through the clouds
簒奪の勝機
A chance for usurpation victory
覚悟を宿命に突きつけて
Thrust your resolve into fate
荒野を駆ける
Running through the wasteland
乱世に挑む
Challenging the turbulent world
天下に狂い咲く
Blooming out of season under the heavens
SAGA! SAGA!
よし！一曲目みんなでアダル... 徒花ネクロマンシー！
Alright! The first song with everyone was Adal... Adabana Necromancy!
なんとなく、うまくいった気がする！
I feel like it went well somehow!
あの、下からのジャンプね。めっちゃよかったよ。ありがとう、ありがとう！
Um, that jump from below. It was really great. Thank you, thank you!
よし、気合改め。行ってらっしゃーい！
Alright, renewing my spirit. Here I go!
Pretty fever
作詞 / 作曲 : 田淵 智也
Lyrics / Composition: Tomoya Tabuchi
不意にクエスチョンマークが絡みつくわけ
The reason why question marks suddenly entangle me
けどセルフィッシュさえも踊り出すわ
But even selfishness starts to dance
心天秤のご機嫌どうでしょう
How is the mood of my heart's scale?
ねえ
Hey
瞬間じゃ決まらない思考回路
Thought processes that can't be decided in an instant
右左　不安回路
Left, right, anxiety circuits
A to Zに隙はない
There are no gaps from A to Z
至って　至って　選定EASY?
Completely, completely, is the selection EASY?
軽く言わないでよね
Don't say it so lightly
僕は僕は都合もあるから
Because I have my own circumstances too
とは言ってもそろそろOK
Having said that, it's almost OK
あのね　I like me
You know, I like me
は確定　意地っ子でも
is certain, even if I'm a stubborn child
I know meは言い切れない
I can't say for sure 'I know me'
ためらっても論より証拠
Even if I hesitate, proof is better than theory
悩んだ時間は自信に変換して
Convert the time spent worrying into confidence
耐えないで回ってく世界のいたずら
The world's pranks that keep spinning without ceasing
パラレルみたいに浮かんでくるひとりごと
Soliloquies that float up like parallel lines
僕がいつかそうだ　大人になるまで
Until I eventually, that's right, become an adult
交わらなくたっていいでしょう
It's fine if we don't cross paths, right?
ほら一歩踏み出すタイミング狙い撃ち
Look, sniping the timing to take a step forward
願いを起動する呪文が必要なんです
I need a spell to activate my wishes
I want to changeぐらい言っちゃおうかな
Maybe I'll go ahead and say 'I want to change'
Yeah
飽きてる暇もないほど
To the point where there's no time to get bored
Yeah
奏でるよ　Pretty fever
I'll play it, Pretty fever
I think so... ねえ
I think so... hey
このままじゃ完成度　上げられぬまま
If things stay like this, without being able to increase the quality
Time goes on
そう　幻じゃないでしょう
Yes, it's not an illusion, is it?
わがまま　周りが認めてるプロフィール
Selfishness, a profile recognized by those around me
と目指す未来図の純粋度
And the purity of the future map I aim for
足して二で割って　そんぐらいは見逃して
Add them and divide by two, please overlook at least that much
クエスチョンマークが絡みつくわ
Question marks are entangling me
けどセルフィッシュさえも踊り出すわ
But even selfishness starts to dance
心天秤の裁きは決まってる
The judgment of my heart's scale is already decided
もう
Already
不器用に回ってる世界も好きだよ
I love this clumsily spinning world too
それでも器用に浮かんでくるひとりごと
Still, soliloquies that float up skillfully
困らせちゃうソーリー
Sorry for troubling you
でもでもずっとずっとシークレット
But but, it's a secret forever and ever
知ってなんていらない決まりです
It's a rule that I don't need you to know
驚かせちゃうほど大きい声で
With a voice loud enough to surprise you
Pretty fever
予想を上回って裏切っちゃって
Exceeding expectations and betraying them
覚悟はいいですか
Are you ready?
I like me
絶対譲れないから
Because I absolutely won't back down
カレンダー
Calendar
日めくり
Daily flip
大人なアイツ
That adult-like person
期待かも
Maybe expectation
不安かも
Maybe anxiety
躊躇っても瞬時にWelcome
Even if I hesitate, instant welcome
そんなの自分で決めちゃっていいでしょ
It's okay to decide that yourself, right?
絶えないで変わってく世界のいたずら
A prank of a world that changes without ceasing
パラレルみたいに浮かんでくるひとりごと
Soliloquies floating up like a parallel world
僕がいつかそばで大人になるまで
Until I grow up by your side someday
交じわなくたっていいでしょ
It's okay if they don't mix, right?
新しいPhaseにみんなを連れてくよ
I'll take everyone to a new phase
自画自賛する自負が必要なんです
Pride in self-praise is necessary
I want to change 本気で言っちゃったから
I want to change, because I said it for real
いつでも青春 I can feel
Youth anytime, I can feel
奏でるよ Pretty fever
Playing it, Pretty fever
Oh Pretty fever
わためお疲れ様！
Watame, good job!
あった、あった、あった！
Found it, found it, found it!
大丈夫、大丈夫です、行けるよ！
It's okay, it's okay, you can do it!
そんな不安そうな顔しないで！
Don't make such an anxious face!
頑張って！行ってらっしゃい！
Good luck! Have a good trip!
かっこよく決めちゃって！
Finish it coolly!
ねえ、聞こえてる？
Hey, can you hear me?
インモラリスト
Immoralist
作詞 / 作曲：清 竜人
Lyrics / Composition: Kiyoshi Ryujin
君と共にギリギリの愛
A love on the edge with you
赤裸々にミゼラブルな愛
A nakedly miserable love
ラブはいつもアナーキズムな愛
Love is always an anarchism love
私だけのインモラリストの愛
My own immoralist love
さよなら言えない
Can't say goodbye
わたしはダメだな
I'm no good
わからない
I don't know
自分がわからない
I don't know myself
この気持ち消えそうもない
This feeling doesn't seem like it'll fade
こんなにもなくならない
It won't disappear this much
いけないんだと思えば思うほど加速するの
The more I think I shouldn't, the more it accelerates
もう自分自身が怖いけど
I'm already scared of myself, but
今信じてみるよ
I'll try believing now
何を失っても
No matter what I lose
きみの御許にと決めたの
I've decided to be by your side
たとえ明日になれば
Even if tomorrow comes
消えゆく運命でも
Even if it's a fading fate
わたしを止める
Stopping me
理由にもならないよ
It won't even be a reason
わたしきみの前なら
If it's in front of you
インモラリストだよ
I'm an immoralist
君と共にギリギリの愛
A love on the edge with you
赤裸々にミゼラブルな愛
A nakedly miserable love
ラブはいつもアナーキズムな愛
Love is always an anarchism love
私だけのインモラリストの愛
My own immoralist love
悲しみ 苦しみ 憎しみ おいでよ
Sadness, suffering, hatred, come here
わたしはいつでも迎える覚悟さ
I'm always prepared to welcome them
そんなふうに思えるようにもなったの
That I've come to feel that way
不思議だな
It's strange
出会ってくれてありがとう
Thank you for meeting me
わたし少し強くなれた
I've become a little stronger
涙なんて神様にあげるから
I'll give my tears to God, so
だからお願い自由をください
Please give me freedom
どこにでも行ける翼を
Wings that can go anywhere
たとえ叶うはずもない
Even if it shouldn't come true
何かに襲われても
Even if something attacks me
今のわたしなら
If it's the current me
一歩だって引かないよ
I won't back down even a single step
わたしきみの前なら
If it's in front of you
ヒロイックだよ
I'm heroic
愛したいのに
Even though I want to love
苦しくて
It's painful
届け届け届いて...
Reach, reach, reach...
きみのこころに
To your heart
このわたしのインモラル
This immoral of mine
一人で抱えるには少し重すぎるの
It's a little too heavy to carry alone
もういっそのことすべて捨ててしまおう
I might as well just throw everything away
なんて...
Saying...
...つぶやいて
...murmuring it as I go
眠るけど いつも
to sleep, but always,
きみの夢ばかり
all I do is dream of you.
どうして？わからない。
Why? I don't know.
なんで？なんでこんなに曲が難しいの？
Why? Why is this song so difficult?
ポルカプロデューサー、ポルカちゃん、
Polka Producer, Polka-chan,
助けてー！
Help me!
あー 答えなんて出なくても
Ah, even if the answer doesn't come out,
立ち向かうよ
I'll face it head-on!
さあこれも私の心体すべてが
Come, even this, my entire heart and body,
君と出会って導き出した答え
Is the answer derived from meeting you.
止まらない 止まれない 止まるつもりも
Won't stop, can't stop, no intention of stopping,
きみの御許にと決めたの
I've decided to be by your side.
きみのた今闘うの
I'm fighting for you right now.
だいすき
I love you.
あいしてる
たとえ明日になれば
Even if when tomorrow comes,
消えゆく運命でも
it's my fate to fade away,
わたしを止める
it won't be a reason
理由にもならないよ
to ever stop me.
わたしきみの前なら
If it's in front of you,
インモラリストだよ
I'm an immoralist.
君と共にギリギリのパイ
Right on the edge together with you,
あからさまにクラクラのパイ
Blatantly dizzy and lightheaded,
ラブはいつもアナーキズムのパイ
Love is always an anarchic struggle,
私だけのインモラルなパイ
My own personal immoral fight.
あくあ様～！ごめんね難しい曲振って！
Aqua-sama! Sorry for giving you such a hard song!
あくあ様、あくあ様は安定ですわ。
Aqua-sama, you were rock solid as always.
もうね、可愛くカッコよくビシッと決めちゃって
You were cute, cool, and you just nailed it!
くれました！
Great job!
お気に召すまま
As You Like It
淡々言葉を吐いた
I spoke my words indifferently
あんな思い出に泣いたのは
That I cried over those memories
今日で終わりにしないか
Why don't we end it today?
ワンツーの合図を待って
Waiting for the one-two signal
ユーエンミー手を取り合ったのは
You and me holding hands
僕の勇気ある行動
Was my courageous action
立ち止まらないでいいんだからね
It's okay not to stop
空々しいなこの人生
This life is so hollow
できないだなんて言わないでね
Please don't say you can't do it
言わないでね
Don't say it
今更なんて言わないでね
Don't say it's too late now
僕ら今 さあさあ輪になって回り始める
We're starting to go 'round in a circle now
だんだん嫌になってでも好きになる
Gradually growing tired of it, yet loving it
ねえねえわかんないや自分会議も
Hey, hey, I don't get it, even this inner debate
どんどん中寄ってでも離れてく
Drawing closer together, yet drifting apart
パッパ音に乗って踊り始める
Moving to the beat and starting to dance
散々嫌になってでも好きになる
Grown weary of it, yet still loving it
ねえねえわかんないやこの先ずっと
Hey, hey, I won't understand, from now on
僕の心をシェイクシェイクイェイ
Shake shake my heart, yeah!
正解なんてないのさ
There's no such thing as a correct answer
じゃあ一体どこに向かえば物語は終わりますか
Then where should we head for this story to end?
ワンツーの合図を待って
Waiting for the one-two signal
ユーエンミー手が触れ合ったのは
You and me, our hands touching
僕の勇気ある行動
Was my courageous action
畏まったって意味ないんだって
There's no point in being so formal
恥ずかしがった夢にバイバイです
Say goodbye to those shy dreams
この先ずっとよろしくね
From now on, let's stick together
よろしくね
Let's stick together
君と今 さあさあ交わって目を逸らしあう
You and I, crossing paths and looking away
だんだん嫌になってでも好きになる
Gradually growing tired of it, yet loving it
ねえねえわかんないや自分会議も
Hey, hey, I don't get it, even this inner debate
どんどん様になって崩れ落ちてく
Taking shape, then crumbling away
パッパ触れる前に消えてしまうの
It vanishes before I can even touch it
散々嫌になってでも好きになる
Grown weary of it, yet still loving it
ねえねえわかんないやこの先ずっと
Hey, hey, I won't understand, from now on
わかりあえるまで僕たちは
Until we can truly understand each other
今更なんて言わないでね
Don't say it's too late now
踊り始める
Start to dance
段々嫌になって
Getting more and more sick of it
でも好きになる
But I end up liking it
ねえねえ わかんないや
Hey, hey, I just don't know
自分会議も
Even the meeting in my head
どんどん中に寄って
Gathers more and more inside
でも離れてく
But then it drifts away
ぱっぱ 音に乗って
Pa-pa, riding the sound
踊り始める
Start to dance
散々嫌になって
Getting completely sick of it
でも好きになる
But I end up liking it
ねえねえ わかんないや
Hey, hey, I just don't know
この先もずっと
From now on and forever
僕の心を シェイク シェイク イェーイ
Shake, shake, yeah! My heart
皆様、お疲れ様です！お次はみこち、
Good work, everyone! Next up is Miko-chi!
みこちの番でもうズギャッてね、
It's Miko-chi's turn to just go "zgya!"
異世界ムーブ始まっちゃったらそこも全然楽しんじゃって！
Once the other-world move starts, just enjoy the whole thing!
それではみこち、最初の盛り上げ役よろしく！
Now Miko-chi, take it away as the first hype-builder!
パッパッパラッパ パッパッパラッパ
Pa-pa-pa-ra-pa, pa-pa-pa-ra-pa
パッパッパラッパ パッパッパラッパ...
Pa-pa-pa-ra-pa, pa-pa-pa-ra-pa...
リアルワールド
Real World
作詞：きみコ 作曲：佐々木淳
Lyrics: kimiko / Composition: Jun Sasaki
目が覚めたなら
If I wake up
君が笑って
and you are smiling
そんな世界が続くと思ってた
I thought that kind of world would continue
当たり前には少し足りない
It's a little lacking in normality
歪んだ視界から見てた
Looking through a distorted field of vision
青い夜
at the blue night
何度目の朝で
In which morning was it?
打ち明けた恋のように
Like a love that was confessed
少し酸っぱいままで出かけたなら
If I went out while it was still a little sour
近付いてく ぼくらデリケート
Getting closer, we are delicate
淡い夢を見せてあげよう
Let me show you a faint dream
たまにはいいことあるかも
Maybe something good will happen once in a while
ご褒美にはチョコレート
For a reward, some chocolate
甘い夢を見れたら
If I could have a sweet dream
それがすべてだなんて
saying "that's everything"
笑い飛ばそう
let's laugh it off
あいまいだって
Even if it's vague
だいたいだって
Even if it's mostly so
続く気がして夜空をあおいだ
I felt like it would continue and looked up at the night sky
なんとなくかな
Maybe just because
見えた景色が
the scenery I saw
新しい世界へ ほらね
To a new world, look
導くよ
it'll guide you
回り続ける
Keep on turning
この星はだれのもの？
Who does this planet belong to?
難しい話なら食後にして
If it's a difficult topic, save it for after dinner
パッパッパラッパ パッパッパラッパ
Pa-pa-pa-ra-pa, pa-pa-pa-ra-pa
パッパッパラッパ パッパッパラッパ...
Pa-pa-pa-ra-pa, pa-pa-pa-ra-pa...
近付いてく ぼくらデリケート
Getting closer, we are delicate
淡い夢を見せてあげよう
Let me show you a faint dream
たまにはいいことあるかも
Maybe something good will happen once in a while
ご褒美にはチョコレート
For a reward, some chocolate
甘い夢を見れたら
If I could have a sweet dream
それがすべてだなんて
saying "that's everything"
笑い飛ばそう
let's laugh it off
あの角でスパスパストレート
A straight puff at that corner
見えないフリしたかった
I wanted to pretend I didn't see it
向き合えば聞こえた
If I faced it, I could hear it
手招きする声
A beckoning voice
いくつかのバリケード
Several barricades
交わせ
Evade them
知れば知るほど
The more I know
分からなくもなるくらい
the more I don't understand
不思議な世界
a mysterious world
手と手 目と目 ひとりとひとり 出会って
Hand to hand, eye to eye, one person and another met
ふたりになる You & Me
And became two, you & me
Turn up the funky beat!
Turn up the funky beat.
That's for You & Me
That's for you & me.
Turn up the funky beat!
早さテロビト It's only for You & Me
Speed of a Terobit, it's only for you & me
瞳にキラキラ ワンダーランド
Sparkling wonderland in my eyes
夜空にキスした バタフライ
A butterfly that kissed the night sky
おいでよエンジェル
Come over, Angel
一緒にムーンライト
Under the moonlight together
恋はデコレーション (Yeah! Yeah!)
Love is decoration (Yeah! Yeah!)
まるでストロベリー
Just like a strawberry
甘いリズムの上で
On top of a sweet rhythm
躍らすウェイブ
Making the waves dance
降り注ぐ大きなハピネス飾ろう
Let's decorate with the massive pouring happiness
二人だけの世界
A world for just the two of us
いくつもの鍵で 君と扉を開ける (Last! Love!)
Opening the door with you using many keys (Last! Love!)
星のジュエリー 降り注ぐ Shining my dream
Starry jewelry pouring down, shining my dream
胸ひろげて (It's) your dream
Open your heart, it's your dream
手と手 目と目 ひとりとひとり 出会って
Hand to hand, eye to eye, one person and another met
ふたりになる You & Me
And became two, you & me
他人じゃないって それだけで
Just the fact that we're no longer strangers
Good morning, Good morning 始まりでしょ
Good morning, Good morning, it's the beginning, right?
夜が朝に 季節が花に 出会って
Night meets morning, seasons meet flowers
未来になる You & Me (With the beat!)
And become the future, you & me (With the beat!)
愛よりもっと ラブな笑顔で
With a smile more 'love' than love itself
終わんない HAPPY DANCE (Out of the stage!)
A never-ending happy dance (Out of the stage!)
手と手 目と目 つないだドキドキ感
Hand to hand, eye to eye, the heart-pounding feeling of connection
桃色ケーキ どんだけ食べても 全然ヘルシー
Pink cake, no matter how much you eat, it's totally healthy
見つめたその 両目の中はヤバい
Gazing into those eyes is dangerous
きらめく星の 数がハンパない
The number of twinkling stars is insane
虹色シューズで 時間旅行 (What's up!)
Time travel in rainbow shoes (What's up!)
いたずら小悪魔は ベイビーフェイス (Oh yeah!)
The mischievous little devil has a baby face (Oh yeah!)
何度もレッスン ぼくの気分 (Oh yeah!)
Practicing over and over, that's my mood (Oh yeah!)
ドキドキしたいわ (Come on!)
I want to feel my heart pound (Come on!)
指先にキラリ ネイルのブルーで (You're so hot!)
Sparkling on my fingertips with blue nails (You're so hot!)
パラダイス 空の欠片 確かめたいな
I want to confirm a fragment of the sky in paradise
二人だけで (It's time!)
Just the two of us (It's time!)
見つめあうたびに おもちゃ箱を抜け出す (Last! Love!)
Every time we gaze at each other, we escape from the toy box (Last! Love!)
恋のメロディ つかまえて Growing my dream
Catch the melody of love, growing my dream
君を追いかけて (In) your dream
Chasing after you, in your dream
手と手 目と目 ひとりとひとり 出会って
Hand to hand, eye to eye, one person and another met
ふたりになる You & Me
And became two, you & me
君がいるって それだけで
Just the fact that you're here
Sunny day, Sunny day 革命なの
Sunny day, Sunny day, it's a revolution
音が歌に 心が声に 出会って
Sound meets song, heart meets voice
言葉になる You & Me (With the beat!)
And become words, you & me (With the beat!)
愛よりもっと フルなボリュームで
At a volume even fuller than love
伝えたい BABY LOVE
I want to convey my baby love
One, two!
いくぜ!
Let's go!
Three, four! Now ready, too!
もっともっと熱い ステージへ!
To an even hotter stage!
Come on, everybody 地平線まで
Come on, everybody, to the horizon
スタートからゴールまで 愛のファンファーレ 鳴らせ!
From start to finish, sound the fanfare of love!
どんなハチャメチャ 待ってても
No matter what craziness awaits
後悔先に 立たず
It's no use crying over spilled milk
願い続け ていれば リアルになる いつかは
If you keep wishing, it will become real someday
そんじゃ、いくぜ! BIG BANG!
Alright, let's go! BIG BANG!
手と手 目と目 ひとりとひとり 出会って
Hand to hand, eye to eye, one person and another met
ふたりになる You & Me
And became two, you & me
昨日じゃないって それだけで
Just the fact that it's not yesterday
Good morning, Good morning 始まりでしょ
Good morning, Good morning, it's the beginning, right?
夜が朝に 季節が花に 出会って
Night meets morning, seasons meet flowers
未来になる You & Me (With the beat!)
And become the future, you & me (With the beat!)
愛よりもっと ラブな笑顔で
With a smile more 'love' than love itself
終わんない HAPPY DANCE
A never-ending happy dance
Lucky, Lucky, Love! You & Me!
Go! Go! Go! Go! That's for You & Me!
Go! Go! Go! Go! Turn up the funky beat!
Go! Go! Go! Go! 早さテロビト
Go! Go! Go! Go! Speed of a Terobit
It's only for You & Me だから Check it out, check it out, J!
It's only for You & Me, so check it out, check it out, J!
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
Omaru Polka and Watame!
Gamble Rumble!
Gamble Rumble
盛り上がる準備 できてるか!?
Are you ready to get hyped!?
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
ぶち上げてけ! OK! Hey!
Let's raise it up! OK! Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey! どんな姿でもいい ノりにノれ!
Hey! Hey! Hey! No matter what you look like, just ride the vibe!
Bring it back! Rock and Roll!
bring it back hey rock'n'roll
Bring it back!
bring it back hey
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
Watame!
Life goes on 満足してた
Life goes on, I was satisfied
少しの希望だけで
With just a little bit of hope
待ってれば 誰かが未来 決めてくれていた
If I waited, someone else would decide the future for me
Just get it back Your back Pick it back up!
なんて小さい自分なんだろう? Bust it up!
How small of a person am I? Bust it up!
Here we go! One, two!
Move it up and break it!
今すぐ夢まで走ろう
Let's run to our dreams right now
Vive la revolution!
Let's go!
Gamble, you gotta chance to make a Rumble
ギリギリのステージ
On the edge of the stage
Oh yeah
Gamble, you gotta dive into the scramble
1ミリも迷わず
Without a moment's hesitation
守るべきモノなんて 実はそんなに無い
There really aren't that many things I should protect
少しだけ強がって 賭けましょう全部
Let's pretend to be a little tough and bet it all
Play the game
暴挙、自分だし、視線を削って過ごしていた
Recklessness, it was me, spending time cutting through glances
代償に手に入れたのは古臭いモラル
What I got in exchange was an old-fashioned moral
臆病なこの群れから今バスタ
Leaving this cowardly herd now
何も持ってないで 飛び出そう
Let's jump out with nothing
Gamble, you gotta chance to make a Rumble
研ぎ澄まされていく
Becoming sharpened
Oh yeah
Gamble, you gotta dive into the scramble
直感を信じて
Trusting my intuition
本命の君の愛 以外はいらなくて
I don't need anything other than your true love
少しでも迷うもの 捨てましょう
Let's throw away everything that makes us hesitate, even a little
It's gonna feel so bad
Gamble, you gotta chance to make a Rumble
溢れ出す目眩が
The overflowing dizziness is...
Gamble, you gotta dive into a scramble!
弾けそうなラストゲーム
Like a last game about to burst
Gamble, you gotta chance to make a Rumble
ギリギリのステージ
On the edge of the stage
Oh yeah
Gamble, you gotta dive into the scramble
1ミリも迷わず
Without a moment's hesitation
一瞬の選択で すべてを失くしても
Even if I lose everything in a moment's choice
後悔は見せないで 明るく負けて泣きましょう
Don't show regret, let's lose cheerfully and cry
Bring back yo, it's the right time, hey boy rock'n roll
3, 2, 1, Break down!
ez do dance
作詞/作曲 小室哲哉
Lyrics/Composition: Tetsuya Komuro
I can hear my voice 今 始まる
I can hear my voice, it's starting now
Midnight time から この場所で
From midnight time, at this place
行くあてが同じ仲間と すべての嘘脱ぎ去る
With friends heading to the same destination, taking off all lies
何もなくて道もなくて 踊る君はどこから
With nothing and no road, where are you dancing from?
逃げているのさ 行くのさ 不思議なほどまぶしい
Running away, going, it's mysteriously bright
誘う夢 語り合って 絆なめ合ってるだけだし
Talking about the inviting dreams, just licking each other's bonds
Easy go easy go 笑顔だけ ひとときの輪をつなぐよ
Easy go easy go, only smiles connect the wheel for a moment
I've got a feeling 抜け出していく 街が目覚めるころ
I've got a feeling, as I break away just as the city wakes up.
朝焼けに口づけてる 波も抱きしめている
Kissing the morning glow, embracing the waves as well.
Ez Do Dance Ez Do Dance 踊る君を見てる
Ez Do Dance, Ez Do Dance, I'm watching you dance.
Ez Do Dance Ez Do Dance 君だけを見ている
Ez Do Dance, Ez Do Dance, I'm looking only at you.
Ez Do Dance Ez Do Dance 踊る君を見てる
Ez Do Dance, Ez Do Dance, I'm watching you dance.
Ez Do Dance Ez Do Dance 君だけを見ている
Ez Do Dance, Ez Do Dance, I'm looking only at you.
欲しいものはいつだって 不意に遭遇する
The things I want, I always encounter them unexpectedly.
見えない明日 突然に 巡り合えるときめき
The invisible tomorrow, the excitement of a sudden encounter.
午前5時 永遠の ルール変わる瞬間
5 AM, the moment the eternal rules change.
きっと愛なんて 呼べるものじゃないけど
It's surely not something you could call love, but...
I've got a feeling 抜け出していく 街が目覚めるころ
I've got a feeling, as I break away just as the city wakes up.
朝焼けに口づけてる 波も抱きしめている
Kissing the morning glow, embracing the waves as well.
Ez Do Dance Ez Do Dance 踊る君を見てる
Ez Do Dance, Ez Do Dance, I'm watching you dance.
Ez Do Dance Ez Do Dance 君だけを見ている
Ez Do Dance, Ez Do Dance, I'm looking only at you.
Ez Do Dance Ez Do Dance 踊る君を見てる
Ez Do Dance, Ez Do Dance, I'm watching you dance.
Ez Do Dance Ez Do Dance 君だけを見ている
Ez Do Dance, Ez Do Dance, I'm looking only at you.
3, 2, 1, Better!
Yo! Yeah! Yeah! Oh! Come on!
I like that, I guess, Keep up the beat like it
Jack Black, all the night, so happy, so yeah!
Get moving, my joiners, shake your body, shake everybody
体の芯まで感じる瞬間 時間の壁まで弾けるリズム
The moment you feel it to your core, a rhythm that bursts through the wall of time.
I've got a feeling 抜け出していく 街が目覚めるころ
I've got a feeling, as I break away just as the city wakes up.
朝焼けに口づけてる 波も抱きしめている
Kissing the morning glow, embracing the waves as well.
Ez Do Dance Ez Do Dance 踊る君を見てる
Ez Do Dance, Ez Do Dance, I'm watching you dance.
Ez Do Dance Ez Do Dance 君だけを見ている
Ez Do Dance, Ez Do Dance, I'm looking only at you.
Ez Do Dance Ez Do Dance 踊る君を見てる
Ez Do Dance, Ez Do Dance, I'm watching you dance.
Ez Do Dance Ez Do Dance 君だけを見ている
Ez Do Dance, Ez Do Dance, I'm looking only at you.
I've got a feeling 抜け出していく 街が目覚めるころ
I've got a feeling, as I break away just as the city wakes up.
朝焼けに口づけてる... Thank you Towa-sama! Yeah!
Kissing the morning glow... Thank you, Towa-sama! Yeah!
さあ、そしてDJタイムが終わりまーした！
Now then, the DJ time has come to an end!
次は誰かな？おっ、フレア！じゃあポルカは客席側に移るわ！
Who's next? Oh, Flare! Then Polka will move over to the audience side!
後で、ちょっと3人曲あるから、その時はまたよろしくー！
Later on, there's a song for the three of us, so I'll see you then!
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to try begging me.
おねだりフレアちゃーん！
Onegai Flare-chan!
ダーリン あなたは私の言うこと全然聞かない
Darling, you don't listen to anything I say at all.
あれほどやめてと言ったタバコもお酒も 毎日二箱七回一日たりとも欠かさず
The cigarettes and alcohol I told you so much to quit, two packs and seven drinks every single day without fail.
肝臓やられてお釈迦になっても 看病してあげないんだから
Even if your liver gives out and you kick the bucket, I'm not going to nurse you.
あーやこーや言うこと聞かない あなたのハートは真っ黒です
Your heart that won't listen to this or that is pitch black.
言いたいことは言わないし
You don't say what you want to say.
行きたいとこからやりたいことまで決めてるくせにたまりま専務
Even though you've decided everything from where you want to go to what you want to do, I can't stand it.
ねえ そんなの馬鹿みたいじゃない そうじゃない じゃない じゃない
Hey, isn't that just stupid? That's not it, not it, not it.
言いたいことがあるならパッと言えば？
If you have something to say, why don't you just say it?
いつも思わせぶりな感じで 察してほしい感じで
Always acting suggestive, acting like you want me to guess.
わざと口にしないのずるくない？ 馬鹿じゃないの？
Isn't it unfair that you purposely don't say it? Are you stupid?
お願いダーリン 見て聞いて 欲しいのは形のないもの
Please, darling, look and listen. What I want is something without a form.
馬鹿にしないで 見て聞いて 覗いてよ瞳の奥の方
Don't make fun of me, look and listen. Take a peek into the depths of my eyes.
まっすぐ見つめて おねだりしてみてほしいの
Look straight at me. I want you to try begging me.
ダーリン 私はあなたの気持ちを全然知らないわ
Darling, I don't know your feelings at all.
あれほど熱心に見つめてきたのに今ではすっかり知らんぷり
Even though you looked at me so intently, now you're completely playing dumb.
ていうかそれって胡座をかいてるだけなんじゃないですか？
I mean, aren't you just resting on your laurels?
ぶっちゃけ下先三寸あなたのせいで私のハートはボロボロです
To be honest, because of your glib tongue, my heart is in tatters.
つれない時はつれないし
When you're cold, you're cold.
そっちがなかなか言い出さないからいつも私が舵取り専門
Since you won't speak up, I'm always the one taking the lead.
ねえ なんだか馬鹿みたいじゃない そうじゃない じゃない じゃない
Hey, doesn't it feel a bit stupid? That's not it, not it, not it.
こんなことさせてちゃダメ出し
I can't let you keep doing this.
どこか足元見てる感じで 値踏みされてる感じで
Feeling like you're taking advantage of me, like you're appraising me.
駆け引きやら勝ち負けじゃなくない？
Isn't it not about tactics or winning and losing?
そういう面倒くさいことしてるから面倒くさい
It's annoying because you're doing such annoying things.
寡黙なダーリンねえ聞いて
Taciturn Darling, hey, listen
切なさは飾りじゃないのよ
Sadness isn't just for show
よそ見しないで 逃げないで
Don't look away, don't run away
触ってよ 心の奥の方
Touch me, deep in my heart
一瞬のことじゃない
It's not just for a moment
せーの！
Ready, go!
おねだりしてみてはくれないの？
Won't you try begging for me?
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
言葉にできない臆病さは
This cowardice I can't put into words
したたかさではないのよ
Isn't a sign of toughness
ホントそれな！
So true!
甘えてないで 口に出してよ
Don't be spoiled, say it out loud
もう ちゃんとこっち向いてったら！
Geez, look this way properly!
ハイ！
Hai!
お願いダーリン見て聞いて
Please, Darling, look and listen
欲しいのは形のないもの
What I want is something without a form
よっほー！
Yoo-hoo!
馬鹿にしないで見て聞いて
Don't make fun of me, look and listen
覗いてよ 瞳の奥の方
Peer into the depths of my eyes
ハイ！
Hai!
寡黙なダーリン 寝てないで
Taciturn Darling, don't be asleep
暴いてよ 私の素顔を
Expose my true face
お願いダーリン そばにいて
Please, Darling, stay by my side
触らせて 心の奥の方
Let me feel deep in my heart
ハイ！
Hai!
真っ直ぐ見つめて
Stare straight at me
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to try begging for me
オー！
Oh!
ワーイ！
Yay!
お願いダーリン
Please, Darling
かわいい！
So cute!
せーの！ 1 2 3 はい！
Ready? 1 2 3 go!
ぽん！
Pon!
はっはっはっはっはっはいや
Ha ha ha ha ha ha iya...
これよりご覧いただきますのは
傾奇者たちの栄枯盛衰
What you are about to see
is the rise and fall of the eccentrics
時代は常に日進月歩
付いてってよ 老若男女
Times are always progressing rapidly
Keep up, everyone, young and old
一見は勧善懲悪 悪者どもを一刀両断
At a glance, rewarding good and punishing evil,
cutting down the wicked in one stroke
でもホントにそれだけで楽しいの？
But is that really all that's fun?
もうなんだって こんにゃく問答
Whatever it is, it's a nonsensical dialogue
はっはっはっはっはっはいや ぽん！
Ha ha ha ha ha ha iya pon!
どこからともなく現れて
すぐどこか行っちゃって神出鬼没
Appearing out of nowhere and
disappearing instantly, ever-elusive
チャンスを待ったら一日千秋
追いかければ東奔西走
Waiting for a chance feels like an eternity,
chasing after it leads all over the place
時代は常に千変万化 人の心は複雑怪奇
Times are always ever-changing,
the human heart is complex and mysterious
でも本気でそんなこと言ってんの？
But are you really serious about that?
もうどうにも満身創痍
Now completely covered in wounds
ああ 巡り巡って
Ah, going round and round
夜の街
The night streets
キミは 合図出し
You give the signal
踊りだす
And start to dance
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Magnificently, like scattering flower petals
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪も振り乱して
With hair flying wildly
一昨日、昨日
The day before yesterday, yesterday
今日と、明日と、明後日と
Today, and tomorrow, and the day after
この宴は続く
This banquet continues
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ！
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart!
一心不乱に回レ！
Spin with all your heart!
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is the Snow, Moon, and Flowers
この世に平安訪れるの？
のべつ幕無し丁々発止
Will peace ever visit this world?
A continuous, heated exchange
兵ども千客万来 ひしめき合う群雄割拠
Warriors coming in crowds, a struggle for supremacy
伸るか反るか一攫千金
気が付いたら絶体絶命
Sink or swim, a sudden fortune
Before you know it, a desperate situation
でも本音のとこ、どうなってんの？
But deep down, what's really going on?
もうまったく奇想天外
Simply fantastic and unexpected
ああ たどりたどって
Ah, tracing and tracing
夜の街
The night streets
迷い 一つなく
Without a single hesitation
踊りだす
Start to dance
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Magnificently, like scattering flower petals
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪も振り乱して
With hair flying wildly
一昨日、昨日
The day before yesterday, yesterday
今日と、明日と、明後日と
Today, and tomorrow, and the day after
この宴は続く
This banquet continues
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ！
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart!
一心不乱に回レ！
Spin with all your heart!
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is the Snow, Moon, and Flowers
花で一つ、鳥で二つ
One for the flowers, two for the birds
手打ち鳴らす
Clap your hands
風で三つ、月出て四つ
Three for the wind, four for the moon
鳴らす 鳴らす...
Ring it, ring it...
花で一つ、鳥で二つ
One for the flowers, two for the birds
手打ち鳴らす
Clap your hands
風で三つ、月出て四つ
Three for the wind, four for the moon
鳴らす 鳴らす...
Ring it, ring it...
今〜は〜
Now~ is~
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Magnificently, like scattering flower petals
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪も振り乱して
With hair flying wildly
一昨日、昨日
The day before yesterday, yesterday
今日と、明日と、明後日と
Today, and tomorrow, and the day after
この宴は続く
This banquet continues
踊れ　歌え　一心不乱に回れ
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart
今宵は何曜日か？
What day of the week is it tonight?
水木金？
Wed, Thu, Fri?
土日月火？
Sat, Sun, Mon, Tue?
はっ！はっ！はっ！はっ！はいっ！はっ！はっ！はっ！はいっ！
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Hai! Ha! Ha! Ha! Hai!
ぽーん！
Pon!
ここまで来たらもう最後のお祭りだ！全員で行くぞー！うおおおお！
Now that we've come this far, it's the final festival! Let's go everyone! Uooooo!
HOLOGRAM CIRCUS
作詞 / 作曲：なつめ千秋
Lyrics / Composition: Natsume Chiaki
ウェルカム！
Welcome!
今日はポルカプロデュースライブ！
Today is the Polka-produced live!
そしてポルカの誕生日ライブにお越しいただき、本当に本当にありがとうございます！
And thank you so, so much for coming to Polka's birthday live!
たくさんの仲間たちが来てくれて、すっごい嬉しいです！
I'm so happy that so many of my friends came!
語彙が無くなっちゃった！あははは！
I've run out of words! Ahahaha!
それでもみんなが横に居るからポルカは頑張っていられます！
But because everyone is by my side, Polka can keep doing her best!
ありがとうございます！そしてまた次の誕生日、これからもよろしくね！
Thank you! And for the next birthday, please keep supporting me!
準備はできてますか？行くぜ！Are you ready?
Are you ready? Let's go! Are you ready?
さあさあ近くにおいで　きっと誰もが仰天
Come, come, come closer. Surely everyone will be amazed.
奇想天外なショーの始まりさ
It's the start of a fantastic show.
ぐっと惹かれるでしょう？
You'll be strongly attracted, right?
おっと押さないでね
Oops, don't push.
それでは準備OKですか？
So, are you ready?
愉快な動物たち　玉乗りピエロ
Cheerful animals, ball-rolling clowns.
ハラハラドキドキしちゃうでしょ
It'll make your heart pound with excitement, right?
真っ赤な輪くぐらせ　綱渡りして
Going through the bright red hoop, walking on the tightrope.
ちょっとくらいのドジなんてご愛嬌よ
A little bit of clumsiness is just part of the charm.
Come on! Light up!
とっておきのライブ　ボーッとしてないで
A special live. Don't just stand there blankly.
もっとさ　もっと　手を叩こう！
More, more, let's clap our hands!
ほらほらついておいで　目も回るような
Look, look, come along. A circus that makes your head spin.
サーカス　きっとここだけだよ
It's definitely only here.
ホログラムみたい　キラキラ
Like a hologram, sparkling
奇跡が踊る
miracles dance.
いつかは世界中を
Someday I'll
虜にしちゃうぞ
captivate the whole world.
はい！
Hai!
行くぜ、2番！みこち！
Let's go, part 2! Mikochi!
うーん　明日の演目はどうしよっかな
Hmm, what should tomorrow's program be?
屋根裏で秘密の作戦会議さ
A secret strategy meeting in the attic.
いっぱいの観客席　あっと驚くような
A full audience. Let's show them
とびきりのショーを見せましょう
an extraordinary show that will surprise them.
思い付いたら　ジッとしてられない
Once I think of it, I can't sit still.
座員を引き連れて Let's go!
Taking the troupe along, Let's go!
ねえあれがやりたい　これもやりたい
Hey, I want to do that, I want to do this too.
どうして時間って足りないの？
Why isn't there enough time?
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
みんな！最後まで盛り上がっていけー！うおおおお！行くぜ！
Everyone! Keep getting excited until the end! Uooooo! Let's go!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
手拍子、お願いしまーす！
Clap your hands, please!
ペンライト振ってる人はもっともっと振って！みんなの色、振っちゃって！
Those waving penlights, wave them more and more! Wave everyone's colors!
最後行きます
Here's the last part.
上手くいかなくって　空回りってばかりで
When things don't go well and I'm just spinning my wheels.
少し落ち込んじゃう日もあるけれど
There are days when I feel a little down,
見ててね
but watch me.
大丈夫！いつまでも
It's okay! I can't
クヨクヨしてらんないし
mope forever.
顔を上げて　今日のステージがほら
Lifting my head, look, today's stage is
ね！待ってるのさ
See! It's waiting for us.
ポルカ！ポルカ！ポルカ！ポルカ！ポルカ！ポルカ！
Polka! Polka! Polka! Polka! Polka! Polka!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you very much!
先輩たちと一緒に歌ってもらって！ポルカ降ります！ありがとうございます！
I had the senpais sing with me! Polka is coming down! Thank you very much!
やばい、もうめっちゃテンション上がっちゃって！ドギマギしちゃってるんで！あれ？ちょっと待って、時間がわかんない！え、もうでも、まだ大丈夫だよね！？
Oh no, I'm getting so pumped up! My heart is pounding! Wait? Hold on, I don't know the time! Uh, but it's still okay, right!?
いくぜ！
Let's go!
強く強く願うんだ　どんな夢だって
Wish strongly, strongly. Any dream,
そうきっと叶うはず
yes, surely it will come true.
何も怖くない　ポルカの声は全部　ちゃんと届いてるよ
Nothing is scary. All of Polka's voice is reaching properly.
さあ新しい次元　新しい舞台へ
Now to a new dimension, to a new stage.
もっとさ　もっと　突き進もう！
More, more, let's push forward!
まだまだついておいで　笑い転げちゃう
Keep following us. A circus that will make you
サーカス　絶対ここだけだよ
roll with laughter. It's definitely only here.
初めての仲間　景色に心も踊る
First friends. My heart dances with the scenery.
今にも世界中を　虜にしちゃうから
Because I'm about to captivate the whole world.
そして、結果発表のときがやってきた……
And then, the time for the result announcement has come...
優勝は……
The winner is...
尾丸ポルカ率いる『ホローバックプロデュース』です。おめでとうございます！！
The winner is "Hollow Back Produce" led by Omaru Polka. Congratulations!!
(ハァ……ハァ……)
(Heavy breathing/Crying)
え……？私達が……優勝……？
Eh...? We... won...?
え……あぅ……
Eh... au...
嬉しいっ……！！
I'm so happy...!!
ありがとう……ありがとうみんな！！
Thank you... Thank you, everyone!!
ここまで来られたのも本当にみんなのおかげです
I'm only here today thanks to all of you.
ありがとうございました！！これからもよろしくお願いしますっ！！
Thank you so much!! Please continue to support us!!
えっ？ご褒美に宣伝させていただいてもいいんですか？わーい！！
Eh? Can I do a promo as a reward? Yay!!
というわけで、尾丸ポルカ誕生日記念2022の
So, the Omaru Polka Birthday Celebration 2022
グッズが販売開始されましたー！
merchandise is now on sale!
こちら、誕生日記念フルセットはなんと記念グッズ3種類、
This Birthday Celebration Full Set includes 3 types of goods,
記念ボイス1種類に、尾丸ポルカ直筆サイン入り、
1 type of voice, and an Omaru Polka handwritten autograph,
きらこ先生描き下ろしチェキ風ブロマイドカードが付いてくる！
along with a Cheki-style bromide card drawn by Kirako-sensei!
カードって、めっちゃテンション上がるよな！
Cards really get you excited, don't they!
こちら、えーその他単品販売もございます。
These are also available for individual purchase.
なんと！ラバーマット！こちら3000円はきらこ先生描き下ろし！
Look! A rubber mat! This 3,000 yen item is drawn by Kirako-sensei!
めちゃくちゃ可愛いですよね！これあのね本当に、おー、なんだろ、ポルカ、
It's so cute, isn't it! This is really, like, Polka,
「お前だけの尾丸ポルカだよ」っていうところをイメージしております。どうでしょうか。
giving off an "Omaru Polka only for you" vibe. What do you think?
ポルカ、あなた、あなたに、あなたにしか見せない尾丸ポルカ。可愛いでしょ。うふふふ。
Polka... an Omaru Polka only for you. Cute, right? Ufufufu.
というわけで、こちらさらに全世界お揃い宣言！
And so, this is a worldwide matching declaration!
隠れポルカ推しリュック！こちら7000円になります！
The "Hidden Polka Fan" Backpack! This one is 7,000 yen!
あー、もうこれね、現地で使いたい！絶対使いたい！
Ah, I want to use this at venues! I definitely want to!
なんならポルカもこのラバーマットのところで一緒に背負ってるから！お揃いなんだよ！
In fact, Polka is carrying it in the rubber mat illustration too! We'll be matching!
ポルカとお揃いな上に、さらにこれをつけてる、えー全員もお揃いになるので全世界お揃いになりますね、ということで。
Besides matching with Polka, everyone who has this will be matching too, so the whole world will be matching.
もしね、あの現地に行く機会など、お外を歩く機会があれば、ま、これを背負っちゃって、というわけで。
So if you have a chance to go to a venue or walk outside, just carry this.
ま、普段使いめちゃくちゃできるんだよね、これ。座員くんのこれね、チャームがついてる上に、
Actually, you can totally use this every day. It has a Zain-kun charm, and...
裏地がね、なんとあらあらあらあら、これね尾丸ポルカ柄なんですよ。もういい仕事してくれますね。
the lining is, oh my, it's an Omaru Polka pattern! They did a great job.
マジでちょうどいいサイズ感。学生さんも、社会人の休日にもめちゃくちゃ合います。
It's a really good size. It suits students and working people on their days off perfectly.
そしてそしてこちら大注目のグッズ！
And then, here's a much-anticipated item!
家でも外でも！回らないポルペラヘアバンド！
At home or out! The "Non-spinning Pol-propeller" headband!
こちら2500円になっておりますー。わー。いるよね、これもつけちゃってさー。
This one is 2,500 yen. Yay. You'll want to wear this one too.
これつけて原宿歩きたいけど、あー楽しそう、そうなったら。「お前もポルペラついてんの？」ってなりそうですよね。
I want to walk around Harajuku wearing this. It'd be so fun. People would be like, "You've got a Pol-propeller too?"
ま、普段使いとしては、ま、簡単に顔洗う時の前髪かき上げるのが無難かなーと思うんですが、
For daily use, I think using it to hold back your bangs when washing your face is the standard way,
なんだろう、ポルカよくスタジオとかでこういうの着けてる人見るんで、多分なんかあの、
but I often see people wearing these in studios and such, so maybe...
疲れてる人もこういうの着けたら会社とかでみんなと仲良くなれる気がします。どうでしょうか。個人の意見でございます。
I feel like tired people can wear this to get along with everyone at work. What do you think? Just my personal opinion.
そして、一拍置かせておきます、の、ですがこれ！
And, let me take a breather, but look at this!
記念ボイス！なんと！ASMRになっておりますー！
The commemorative voice! It's actually ASMR!
こちら記念ボイスのASMRボイスはデート帰りの膝枕ボイス。膝枕ボイスー！おおお！
The ASMR voice is a lap-pillow voice after a date. A lap-pillow voice! Ooh!
こちら価格が3000円となっておりますが、お値段以上のものだとポルカは思っております。えへへへ。
The price is 3,000 yen, but Polka thinks it's worth more than that. Ehehehe.
なんてこんな、あーいやもう言えない、もう言葉に表せないけど、最近ちょっとポルカ成分、
How can I say... Ah, I can't say it, words can't describe it, but if you've been lacking Polka lately,
オフポルカ成分なかったよなーって感じの人は、これ絶対聴くとね、めっちゃね、よく眠れると思う。本当に。
or "Off-Polka" lately, if you listen to this, you'll sleep really well. Seriously.
あのね、すごい、もうわがまま言って少し長く取ってしまいましたので、ちょっとお値段がね、こうなってしまったんですが、その分の価値が絶対にあると思うので、
You know, it's great. I was selfish and made it a bit long, so the price ended up like this, but I'm sure it's worth it,
絶対に買ってくれよな。個人の意見です。
so please buy it. Just my personal opinion.
はい、そして気になる販売期間となっておりますこちら！本日2022年1月30日から、
Okay, and here's the sales period! From today, January 30, 2022,
2022年の3月7日、そしてこちら6時。
to March 7, 2022, at 6:00 PM.
J-P-T...
嘘じゃん。
Just kidding.
Japan... Japan Time...
今のカットで！
Cut that part out!
Japan Time, Japan Time...
今のカットで！
Cut that part out!
J-P-T... (笑)
J-P-T... (Laughs)
日本時間の６時まで、18時までとなっております。
They will be available until 6:00 PM, or 18:00, Japan time.
グッズはすべてこちら受注販売商品となっておりますので、
Since all of these items are made-to-order,
慌てずお買い求めください。
please take your time with your purchase.
というわけで、尾丸ポルカがお送りしました、
And with that, your host was Omaru Polka,
ホロライブプロダクションそして尾丸ポルカ生誕祭のライブ、
bringing you the Hololive Production Omaru Polka Birthday Celebration Live.
楽しかったでしょうか？
Did you have a good time?
楽しめたなら何よりです。
If you enjoyed it, that makes me happier than anything.
今日来ていただいたゲストというか、もう一緒にチームの仲間たちって感じなんだけど、
The guests who joined me today—well, they feel more like fellow teammates on the same team now—
ポルカがやりたいようにやらせていただいて、
they let Polka do things exactly the way I wanted to,
そして見てる皆様もやりたいようにやってるポルカを、
and I hope all of you watching saw Polka doing as she pleased
なんとなくぬるま湯っぽい目で見てくれたかなと思っております。
and watched over me with a sort of warm, gentle gaze.
やりたいこと少しはまたやれたかなと思っております。
I think I was able to do a few more of the things I wanted to do.
それではそれでは、ありがとうございました！
And so, and so, thank you very much!